THEODORE JOHNSON

UX RESEARCHER

INFO

ADDRESS

Oswego, 13126, United States

PHONE

6073684228

EMAIL

THEOJOHNS91@GMAIL.COM

LINKS

<u>Academia</u>

LinkedIn

Carbonmade

SKILLS

User-Centered Design

Statistical Analysis

Usability Testing

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

Microsoft Visual Studio/C#

Virtual Reality UX

Wireframing

Storyboarding

Prototyping

Augmented Reality

Adobe Creative Suite

Data Science

Data Analysis

Balsamiq

Axure

PUBLICATIONS

IEEE GEM 2018: Video Game User Experience: To VR, or Not to VR?

Galway, Ireland

Nov 2018

Given the increasing use of VR for video gaming, the current study investigated whether VR gaming might affect the video gaming user experience (UX). We compared three different gaming platforms, namely desktop computer, Oculus Rift, and HTC Vive, in terms of gaming UX satisfaction.

Jun 2019 - Jun 2019

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

UX/AR Research Impact Scholarship Project, SUNY Oswego Computer Science Department

Oswego

May 2019 - Nov 2019

- Working with a community and faculty sponsor to create Augmented Reality Systems for the New York State Parks and Recreation Services at the Historic Fort Ontario.
- Running AR diagnostics, and UX methodology for image recognition and image stabilization.
- Running cognitive analytic testing on the final product and writing/finalizing a research publication based on results of the study.

Human Computer Interaction Graduate Research Assistant, SUNY Oswego Computer Science Department

Oswego. NY

Jan 2019 - Present

- Develop new HCl project ideas and expand on the existing project work in the HCl program
- Perform literature reviews and help supervise students in field who wish to write papers and conduct research.
- Give presentations and help advertise HCI projects on campus.

Deployment Technician, General Services Administration

Syracuse, NY

Aug 2018 - Sep 2019

- Installed, configured and maintained data migration of workstations and software.
- Assisted the client in solving computer related issues and orientation of new equipment as deployed.
- Backed up and restored personal data; and configured new computers for employees.
- Diagnosed and upgraded hardware to ensure optimum level of performance.

Undergraduate Research Assistant in Human Oswego, NY Computer Interaction, SUNY Oswego Computer Science Department

Nov 2017 - May 2018

- Recruited and scheduled over 100 research participants.
- Programmed 10 small-scale experimental applications.
- Contributed to data analysis and dissemination of research findings.
- Utilized Microsoft Office Suite and Statistical Analysis Software for data analytics.
- Usability testing with Oculus Rift, HTC Vive Virtual Reality headsets for various projects.

Process Technician, Corning Incorporated

Corning, NY

Jun 2013 - Aug 2013

 Involved setting up, assembling, maintaining, monitoring, and operating equipment in various operations such as pilot production, research, development labs, and department labs and shops. This included exposure to oscilloscopes, microscopes, and test equipment.

EDUCATION

State University of New York at Oswego, Master of Arts in Human Computer Interaction

Aug 2018 - Dec 2019

State University of New York at Oswego, Bachelors of Arts in Cognitive Psychology

Oswego, NY

Oswego, NY

Aug 2016 - May 2018

Corning Community College, Associate Degree in Applied Science

Corning, NY

Aug 2010 - May 2013

INTERNSHIPS

Augmented Reality Team Impact Scholarship Project, SUNY Oswego Graduate Studies/Fort Ontario

Oswego, NY

May 2019 - Present

SCHOLARSHIPS

SUNY Oswego Graduate Impact Scholar

Oswego, NY

May 2019